Once in a while when I wake up
I find myself crying.
The dream I must have had
I can never recall.
But...
the sensation that I've lost something
lingers for a long time after I wake up.
I'm always searching
for something, for someone.
This feeling has possessed me
I think from that day...
That day when the stars came falling.
It was almost as if...
as if a scene from a dream.
Nothing more, nothing less
than a beautiful view.
Ah, if only our voices speak at night
could ever reach the very edge
of this world, and the time
Instead of fading into air and dust
Then what will the words could ever be?
Farthest words from 'probably'
Let's make a promise, that will never fade.
Let's say it together in count of three, oh
Ah, I'm told that some part of
every wish will be heard
But lately I lost sight
of the truth in those words
I can't even remember when I gave up
believing. What could have been the reason?
Ah, the very moment that the rain will stop
And the place rainbow born and dies
And where the end of this life lies
I've always been insisting there was
something that I've longing for
One day we'll reach to
emotions unexplored unprecedented
We'll high-five love we've yet to discover
and give a kiss to time
The five dimensions keep on teasing me.
But I will keep on looking at you, dear
Let's make a sign for
when we say nice to meet you again
I'm on my way to you,
chasing after your name
Taki. Taki.
Don't you remember me?
My name is...
Mitsuha!
Mitsuha, what are you doing?
Well, it feels incredibly realistic...
What? "Mitsuha"?
Are you half asleep? Breakfast!
Hurry up!
What? What?
Do you want last night's leftovers?
You can have it.
- Good morning.
Mitsuha, you're late!
I'll make breakfast tomorrow.
Is this too much?
Well. It's okay
You're normal today.
You were nuts yesterday.
What are you talking about?
Good morning, everyone.
This is an announcement
from Itomori Town Hall.
Regarding the mayoral election
on the 20th next month,
the election committee...
"Comet to pass by in a month:
Visible to the naked eye"
A comet with an orbital period of
1,200 years will pass by in a month.
The comet will be visible
to the naked eye for several days...
It's time for you to make up with him.
It's an adult matter.
"Position of Cornet Tiamat"
JAXA are preparing to observe
the celestial show of the century.
"Closest on October 4th"
We're going!
Study hard!
Mitsuha!
Morning, Sayaka, Tessie.
Morning.
- Get off.
- Why? Meanie.
- You're heavy.
- That's rude.
You two get along so well.
We do not!
Your hair looks all right today.
What?
Yeah,
- did your grandma exorcise you?
- Exorcise?
You were totally possessed yesterday!
Cut out the occultism.
Mitsuha is just stressed. Right?
Huh? What are you talking about?
You don't remember?
And above all,
restoring the town's fiscal health
to continue its revitalization project!
Only when these are achieved
can a safe and secure community be created!
As the incumbent mayor...
He'll be reelected again anyway.
I heard he's been dishing out the pork.
Hey, Miyamizu.
Morning.
The mayor's kid and
his contractor's kid get along too.
Ew.
Mitsuha!
Stand up straight!
He's strict with his family.
I'm impressed.
So embarrassing.
Pathetic!
Mitsuha.
In front of everybody...
"Who are you?"
"Tasokare" (Twilight)
"Tasokare" means "Who is that" and is
the origin of the word "tasogare-doki."
Twilight, when it's neither day nor night.
When the world blurs and one might
encounter something not human.
Older expressions include "karetaso-doki"
and "kawatare-doki."
I have a question! Not "kataware-doki"?
"Kataware-doki"? I think
that's a local dialect.
I've heard that Itomori's elderly
still use classical language.
"Who are you?"
We're in the boonies, after all.
OK next, Mitsuha.
Yes.
Oh, so you remember your name today.
You don't remember?
Yesterday you forgot
where your desk and locker were.
Your hair is messy with no ribbon.
What? No way! Really?
It was like you had amnesia.
Well,
I do feel like I've been
in a strange dream lately...
A dream about someone else's life?
I can't remember clearly.
I know! That was...
your previous life!
Or maybe
your subconscious
linked to the Everett multiverse...
Stay out of this.
Oh! Tessie, did you write
that in my notebook?
Nothing.
But Mitsuha,
you really were a bit weird yesterday.
Are you feeling alright?
That's so strange. I feel fine.
Maybe you are stressful.
That ritual is coming up, isn't it?
Oh, don't remind me!
I can't stand this town anymore.
It's too small and packed.
I want to graduate and go to Tokyo.
I don't blame you.
There's really nothing in here.
Trains come every 2 hours.
The store closes at 9 p.m.
No bookstore. No dentist.
"Pub Mother" "Pub Cat's Eye"
But have 2 pubs for some reason.
No jobs.
No brides.
Short sunlight hours.
- Give me a break!
- What?
I mean... How about we stop by a cafe?
- A cafe?
- Really?
Where?
Hello.
This is a cafe?
You knew there wasn't one.
Mitsuha just went home.
Things must be rough for her.
Because she is the center stage.
Yeah.
Hey, Tessie.
What?
What will you do after you graduate?
What's this?
Are you asking about my future?
Nothing special.
I'll probably keep on
living a normal life in this town.
I'd rather do that too.
You're not ready yet, Yotsuha.
Listen to the thread's voice.
When you keep twining like that,
emotions will eventually start flowing
between you and the thread.
Threads don't talk.
She means, "Focus."
1,000 years of Itomori's history is etched
into our braided cords.
Listen. 200 years ago...
Here she goes again.
Sandal maker Mayugoro's bathroom caught
on fire and burned down
the whole area around.
The shrine and old documents were destroyed
and this is known as...
The Great Fire of Mayugoro.
The fire has his name? Poor Mayugoro.
So the meaning of our festivals became
unknown and only the formality lived on.
But even if words are lost,
tradition should be handed down.
That's our responsbility
at Miyamizu Shrine.
But that foolish son-in-law...
He not only left Shinto
priesthood but also.
Play politics? He's hopeless.
Have one more, my man.
I'm counting on your help again.
Leave it to me.
You'll get votes from the Kadoiri
and Sakagami Districts.
How's it going with her?
It's not that easy.
I smell corruption.
Don't be ridiculous.
Bring us a few more hot sake.
OK.
Katsuhiko, come help on site this weekend.
Learn how to use explosives.
Yes.
Can't hear you.
Yes!
We both have had enough, don't we?
Is that Yotsuha? She's all grown up.
They're both pretty like their mother.
Hey.
It's the oldest sake in the world.
By chewing on rice, spitting it out,
and letting it ferment, it becomes alcohol.
"Kuchikamisake."
Do the gods appreciate sake made that way?
Of course they do.
Hey, look. It's Miyamizu.
Oh! I could never do that!
Isn't she embarrassed?
I can't believe it.
Cheer up, Mitsuha.
Who cares if a few classmates saw you?
I envy your "pre-pubescent"
carefree attitude.
Why not sell lots of kuchikamisake and
use the money to go to Tokyo?
Where do you get such ideas?
Sell them with photos and making videos.
Name it "Shrine Maiden's Sake."
You'll make money!
"Shrine Maiden's Sake"
No. That breaks the Liquor Tax Law.
That's the problem?
I hate this town! I hate this life!
Please make me a handsome Tokyo boy
in my next life!
What a fool...
Ow!
Ouch...
Where...
Something's there...
Ow!
Taki, Are you up?
It was your turn to cook.
Wake up on time.
I'm sorry.
I'm going now. Drink all the miso soup.
OK.
Go to school even if you're late.
See you.
Have a nice day.
What a strange dream.
"From Tsukasa: Run, you're late!"
What? Who's it from? Tsukasa? Who's that?
I have to use the bathroom.
This is too realistic.
"Shinjuku Station"
I'm in Tokyo.
"Jingu High School"
- Where'd you get it?
- Daikanyama.
The front act at the next gig...
Let's skip club and go to a movie.
Taki!
Arriving at noon, huh? Let's eat lunch.
You ignored my message
Oh, Tsukasa?
At least you sound apologetic.
You got lost?
Yeah.
How could you get lost
on the way to school?
- Uh... Well... I (watashi)...
- Feminine?
I (watakushi)!
I (boku)?
I (ore)?
I was enjoying myself.
It's so festive to me all in Tokyo.
You seem to have a dialect.
Where's your lunch?
- Geez.
- Are you half asleep?
You got something?
Croquette-egg sandwich sounds good!
Thank you.
Let's go to a cafe.
Oh that one? OK. Corning, Taki?
What? What? What?
A cafe?
Nice timberwork up there.
Yeah, they attented to details.
Taki, have you decided?
What? I could live for a month
for the price of this!
What age are you from again?
Hmm. Oh well. It's a dream anyway.
What a great dream.
Oh no, what should I do? I'm late for work!
Your shift is today?
- Go, then.
- Oh, yeah.
Oh! Urn...
Where do I work?
What?
Tables 6, 7, and 10 are waiting!
Table 12! Taki!
Yes.
Here you go.
Uh, zucchini and tomato salad...
We didn't order that.
Taki, I said no more truffles!
Taki, can't hear you!
Taki!
When is this dream going to end?
Hey. Hey waiter.
Oh, yes?
There was a toothpick in the pizza.
We could have gotten hurt.
Good that I noticed earlier.
What do you have to say?
Uh, well...
But...
There are no toothpicks
in an Italian restaurant's...
Excuse me.
Is everything ok?
I'll handle this.
What's wrong with you today?
Please accept our apologies.
Your meal is on the house.
Oh, really?
I hope you weren't hurt.
Urn...
Okudera...
Ms. Okudera.
Ms. Okudera. Thank you...
A stroke of bad luck today.
No, uh...
It definitely was a set-up.
Handled it according to the manual, but...
Oh, Ms. Okudera, your skirt!
You OK?
- What happened?
- It is slashed.
That jerk from earlier?
Now what? Do you remember his face?
No.
Come with me.
Hey, Taki!
Take off your skirt.
Oh! I'll look the other way!
This won't take long.
Done!
Wow, Taki! It looks better than before!
Thank you for saving me today.
Actually, I was concerned about you.
You're weak but quick-tempered.
I like you better today.
Never knew you had a feminine side.
"JR Yamanote Line: 7 min."
What a realistic dream...
Oh, he keeps a diary.
He's so organized.
Wish I lived in Tokyo too.
Oh! That's her!
A crush, maybe?
"Walked to the station
with Ms. Okudera after work,
thanks to my feminine powers!"
"Who are you?"
"Mitsuha"
What is this?
Wha... Wha...
What's going on?
"Thanks to my feminine powers!"
Let's go to a cafe again.
Sorry, I have to go to work.
Do you remember where to go?
Tsukasa, did you prank my phone and...
Oh, never mind. See you.
He's acting normal today.
Yesterday he was kind of cute.
What?
Wha... What?
Taki, you tried to outdo us!
You walked home with her!
Did I really? With MS. Okudera?
What happened afterwards?
I don't really remember.
Oh really, now?
Corning through.
- Hi guys.
- Hello.
Let's make this a good one.
Right, Taki?
"Mitsuha? Who are you?"
"What are you?"
You're not touching your boobs today.
Breakfast is ready! Hurry up!
Boobs?
Morning.
Why is everyone staring at me?
Well you made quite a scene yesterday.
Huh?
"Still life drawing"
Did you see the election posters?
Doesn't matter who wins.
It's all about how to serve up the grants.
Shh! Someone's livelihood depends on it.
They mean me, right?
Well, yeah.
Hey, Mitsuha!
Wha... Wha... I did what?
Mitsuha?
Is this... Could this be...
Could this be that we're really...
In our dreams, that guy and I have...
In our dreams, that girl and I have...
switched places?
At last, hello you've opened your eyes
But, why won't you even look me in
the eyes, what't wrong with you?
You angrily tell me that I'm late
Well, I'm sorry, but I did my best
and running at my fastest pace
I started to understand what's going on.
Taki is a boy my age living in Tokyo.
I switch with Mitsuha at random,
a few times a week unexpectedly.
Sleep triggers it.
The cause is a mystery.
"Condition: Sleep?
Cause: Unknown"
My memory during the switch is hazy
after I wake up.
But we've definitely switched places.
The reactions of the people
around us is the proof. So...
So we need to lay down some rules
to protect each other's lifestyles.
"Strictly forbidden!"
Things to watch out during the switch
"No baths! No looking! No touching!"
and a list of "don'ts."
"Don't waste money! No dialect!
Don't be late!"
We also agreed to leave reports
in our smartphones.
To work together to tide over this
mysterious phenomenon.
But...
- That girl!
- That guy!
Back in the Zenzenzense 'til this day,
been looking everywhere for you
I followed the sound of your innocent
laughter and it guided me in the right way
Even if every piece of you disappeared,
and if it scattered everywhere
Guys are staring! Watch the skirt!
Come on, this is basic!
"Careful With skirts!"
Stop wasting my money!
It's YOUR body eating.
And I'm working too!
"Braided cords..."
Braided cords... I can't do this!
You work too many shifts!
It's because you waste my money!
I wonder if we can push our way through
The countless barriers that's waiting
in the future just beyond our view
Side by side, no way we can lose
We'll beat destiny at its own game
and make it follow our own rules
Grabbed coffee with Ms. Okudera.
You two have a good thing going!
Mitsuha, stop changing my relationships!
Taki, why is a girl in love with me?
You're more popular when I'm you.
"Don't think too much of yourself!"
Don't think too much of yourself!
You don't even have a girlfriend!
You don't have a boyfriend!
- I...
- "Fool"
- "Idiot"
I'm single because I want it!
I feel bad doing this to her
You sure do like your boobs.
We're going now! Get ready!
Comet Tiamat has become visible
to the naked eye for a few days now.
When and where can it be seen?
"Comet Tiamat Reaching Perigee"
Comet Tiamat is moving from east to west
as if to follow the sun.
So it can be seen above Venus...
Why do you wear uniform?
Grandma, why is the body of
our shrine's god so far away?
I don't know. It is because of Mayugoro.
Who's that?
What? He's famous!
Here, Grandma.
Whoa, Mitsuha.
Mitsuha, Yotsuha,
do you know "Musubi"?
Musubi?
Musubi is the old way of calling
the local guardian god.
This word has profound meaning.
It means "Tying thread"
And it also means "Connecting people".
And "The flow of time".
These are all god's power.
So the braided cords that we make
are the god's art
which represent the flow of time itself.
They converge and take shape.
They twist, tangle
sometimes unravel, break,
then connect again.
Musubi is knotting. That's time.
Drink.
Thank you.
I want some too!
That's also Musubi.
Whether it be water, rice, or sake
when a person consumes something and
it joins their soul, that's Musubi.
So today's offering
is an important custom that
connects the god and people.
Hey, I see it!
That's the body of Miyamizu Shrine's god?
Beyond this point is "kakuriyo."
It means the underworld.
It's the underworld!
In exchange for returning to this world,
you must leave behind
what is most important to you.
The kuchikamisake.
The kuchikamisake?
You'll offer it to the god's body.
It's half of you.
Half of Mitsuha...
It's twilight-"kataware-doki"  already.
Kataware-doki?
Oh yeah,
maybe I can see the comet.
The comet?
Oh,
Mitsuha,
you're dreaming right now, aren't you?
Tears? Why?
"I'm almost there. Looking forward to it!"
Ms. Okudera? What's she talking about?
What did Mitsuha do this time?
A date?
A date with Ms. Okudera tomorrow!
Meet at 10:30 a.m. at the station!
Was what I'd planned, but...
Taki.
Sorry. Did you wait long?
Yes. No... Um...
I just got here.
Good. Let's go.
He's so lucky. They must
be together around now...
Hey?
I...
Why?
I wanted to go to this date,
but if it so happens that you
end up going, you better enjoy it!
However, I'm sure you've
never gone out for a date before,
I don't know what to say...
so below are some links
to help you out, you late bloomer.
Really?
"You can get a girlfriend too!"
"I suffer anxiety but got a girl!
"The dos and don'ts of texting."
She's making fun of me.
"Photo exhibition: Nostalgia"
Taki...
You're like a different person today.
Um, Ms. Okudera. Are you hungry?
How about dinner...
Let's call it a day.
Yes.
Taki, you... Sorry if I'm wrong.
You used to have a bit
of a crush on me, right?
But now you like someone else.
No I don't!
Really?
No! That's not true at all.
I wonder.
Oh well. Thanks for today.
See you at work.
By the time the date is over,
the comet will be visible in the sky.
What is she saying?
"Mitsuha Miyamizu"
Oh, it's you, Tessie.
No, I just didn't feel
like going, that's all.
I'm fine.
What? The festival? Well...
Oh yeah, the comet.
Today's it show the peak of its brightness
OK, got it. Later, then.
You just want to see her in a yukata.
What I? No!
I didn't even think about it.
Hey, she sounded kind of upset.
Because she didn't want to listen to
your phone call?
May be she is annoyed by you.
Sorry I'm late.
- Here she is!
- Finally!
- Your... your...
- Oh! What happened, Mitsuha?
Your hair!
Looks kinda funny, I guess?
Is it because of that boy?
Ditched, maybe?
Why do guys associate
cutting hair with breakups?
She said she just felt like it.
Really?
She just felt like cutting
off that much hair?
Oh! Hey! You can see it!
Wow!
The number you have called
is not available...
I'll tell her about this disastrous date
next time we switch,
I thought. But...
For some reason, after that,
Mitsuha and I never switched places again.
"Mountains in Gifu Prefecture"
"Hida mountains"
What... What are you doing here?
Tsukasa told me and here I am!
Tsukasa, I asked you to cover for me
at home and at work.
Takagi will cover your shift.
Leave it to me! But you owe me a meal!
This isn't funny.
- We were worried about you.
- Huh?
You can't go alone.
What if it's a con act?
A con act?
You're meeting an online friend.
Well no, not exactly...
- I think he's using a dating site.
- No!
You've been acting weird lately.
We'll keep an eye on you.
I'm not a kid!
The switching stopped.
My calls and texts didn't go through.
So I decided to go see Mitsuha in person.
I wanted to meet her. But...
What? You don't know where?
The town's scenery is your only clue?
Yes.
And you can't contact her?
What's this all about?
Seriously. What a lousy tour planner.
I did not plan a tour!
Oh well. We'll help you look for her.
Oh how cute! Look!
So annoying.
Oh, it moved!
So it's impossible after all...
What? After all the
trouble we went through?
You haven't done anything.
A Takayama ramen.
Oh, then a Takayama ramen.
- OK. 3 ramens.
- OK.
Can we return to Tokyo today?
We could be cutting it close. I'll check.
Thanks.
Are you all right with that?
I'm starting to feel like
I'm barking up the wrong tree.
Why young man, that's Itomori, isn't it?
It's a very good drawing. Isn't it, dear?
Yeah, it's Itomori. Brings back memories.
He was born in Itomori.
Itomori...
Yes! Itomori Town! That's it!
It's nearby, isn't it?
- What are you...
- Itomori was...
Itomori? No way!
Is it where that comet...
"Keep Out"
Hey. Is this really the place?
No way! Taki must remember wrong.
No. I'm sure it is the place.
This schoolyard. The mountains.
I remember this high school clearly!
That can't be true!
Surely you remember that disaster
that took hundreds of lives 3 years ago!
Died?
Died 3 years ago?
That can't be.
I still have the memos
that she left behind...
They're disappearing...
Comet Tiamat,
with an orbital period of 1,200 years,
"Itomori, the Town that Vanished"
made a close approach to Earth
3 years ago in October.
"Meteor Strikes, Wipes out Town"
Nobody predicted that its nucleus
would split at its perigee.
"Town Annihilated"
"Over 500 dead or missing"
"Itomori, the Town that Vanished"
"October 4, 2013-Itomori vanished."
A fragment of the comet became
a meteor that struck Japan.
"Itomori, comet, damage"
It was the day of the autumn festival.
The point of impact was here.
At 8:42 p.m., it struck where people
were gathered for the festival.
"List of the Names of Victims"
Over 500 people died,
a third of the town's population,
and now nobody lives in Itomori anymore.
Tessie and Sayaka...
"Mitsuha Miyamizu"
That's her?
It has to be some kind of mistake.
This person died 3 years ago!
Just 2, 3 weeks ago, she said to me
that the comet would be visible.
So...
You're dreaming now...
I...
Aren't you?
What did I...
Lively up there.
I'm sorry we could only get one room.
No problem.
How's Taki?
He's still reading articles on Itomori.
Newspapers and magazines
at the time at random it seems.
What?
Nothing. I didn't know you smoke.
Oh. I quit recently, but...
What do you think about Taki's story?
I liked him.
The way he was recently. He was always
a nice guy, but even more so lately.
Like he was trying so hard. It was cute.
What he's saying doesn't
make sense to me...
But I'm sure he met someone
and that someone changed him.
That much is for sure, I think.
"Worst-ever Itomori Cornet Disaster"
It was all just a dream.
I recognized the scenery because
I remembered the news from 3 years ago.
If not that, then... a ghost?
No... Was I fantasizing?
Her name... What was it?
Tsukasa went to take a bath.
Oh, Ms. Okudera.
I, uh... I've been saying
such strange things.
Thank you for coming along today.
No problem.
"Tatara Iron Making Site"
"Braided Cords of Itomori"
Braided cords. How pretty.
Is that a braided cord you're wearing?
Oh, this... I think someone
gave it to me a long time ago.
I wear it sometimes as
kind of a lucky charm...
Who was it?
Why don't you go take a bath, too?
Yes... No.
Someone who makes braided
cords told me before...
The cords represent the
flow of time itself.
The threads twist, tangle,
unravel, and connect again. That's time...
Maybe at that place...
"Around here?"
Taki.
Don't you remember me?
"I have to go somewhere.
"Return to Tokyo without me.
"I'll return later.
"Thanks."
Taki...
Eat this up there.
Your drawing of Itomori... It was good.
They converge and take shape.
They twist, tangle,
sometimes unravel,
then connect again...
Musubi-knotting. That's time.
There it is!
It's really there!
It wasn't just a dream!
From here is the underworld.
It's the sake we brought.
This is her sister's, and this is mine.
Before the comet struck...
So the Mitsuha I know is from 3 years ago?
Our timelines weren't in sync.
Half of her...
Musubi.
If time can really be turned back,
give me one last chance...
A comet!
Your name is Mitsuha.
You're both my treasures.
You're a big sister now.
"Get well soon, Mom."
I'm so sorry, my dears.
Dad, when is Morn going to come home?
I couldn't save her.
Get a hold of yourself!
Who cares about the shrine?
You're the adopted son-in-law!
I loved my wife Futaba.
Not Miyamizu Shrine.
Get out of here!
Mitsuha, Yotsuha,
you'll be with Grandma from now on.
- Who am I?
- "Who are you?"
- No, who are you?
- "Mitsuha"
"Fool"
Don't think too much of yourself.
You don't even have a girlfriend
He's so lucky. They must
be together around now...
I...
I'm going to Tokyo.
What? Hey, Mitsuha!
Grandma, could you do me a favor?
Oh yeah, the comet.
Today's the peak of its brightness...
Mitsuha! Don't stay there!
Mitsuha, get out of there
before the comet strikes!
Mitsuha, get out of there!
Mitsuha! Mitsuha!
Mitsuha!
I'm Mitsuha! She's still alive!
Mitsuha, are you touching...
My sister!
Yotsuha!
Mitsuha has finally lost it.
I'm leaving without her.
She's lost it.
She's completely lost it.
Scary.
Comet Tiamat has been visible
to the naked eye for a few days now.
Tonight it will finally reach
its perigee around 7:40 p.m.,
and will achieve its maximum brightness.
It's tonight. There's still time.
Good morning, Mitsuha.
Oh...
You're not Mitsuha, are you?
You knew, Grandma?
No, but watching the way you behaved lately
triggered some memories.
I also remember seeing strange dreams
when I was a young girl.
Although now I've forgotten about
whose life I was dreaming about.
Forgotten...
Treasure the experience.
Dreams fade away after you wake up.
There were times your mother and I
had similar experiences.
Maybe those dreams that
the Miyamizu people had
were all for what will happen today.
Grandma, listen.
A comet will strike Itomori tonight
and everyone will die.
"Nobody will believe that"?
What a surprisingly
ordinary reply, Grandma.
I won't let them die!
Oh! What happened, Mitsuha?
Your... your hair!
Oh, this. It looked better before, huh?
Oh, that's it?
Forget that! If nothing is done,
everyone will die tonight!
So we have to do something!
Why aren't you at school?
Uh... We have to save the town.
The community wireless system?
Yeah, those speakers you see everywhere.
"Superimposition, frequency"
I see! That could work!
You're awesome, Tessie!
Hey! Don't come so close!
What, embarrassed? Hey, hey!
Stop! You're a girl of marriageable age!
"Club Discontinued-Keep Out"
You're such a nice guy!
Got them. Here's your change.
Sorry, Sayaka.
It's all right.
- What a cheap fee.
- Deal with it.
What about you?
Have you come up with an escape plan?
What? A bomb?
We have water gel explosives
for construction at our storage site.
Broadcast hijacking?
The town's wireless system can be easily
jacked using the startup frequency.
So we can broadcast an evacuation
warning from the school.
The school is outside the disaster area,
so people can evacuate here.
It's... It's totally a crime!
You do the broadcast.
Why?
You're in the broadcast club.
I'm in charge of explosives.
I'll go talk to the mayor.
In the end, the city council
has to evacuate everyone.
I'm his daughter. I can persuade him.
It's a perfect plan.
Oh, whatever.
It's just a what-if fantasy, isn't it?
What? Well...
Not necessarily!
Do you know how Lake Itomori was formed?
"A meteor crater lake
formed 1,200 years ago."
It's a meteor crater!
So one did strike this
area a thousand years ago!
Oh! So that's why...
You're right, Tessie!
Let's do it together!
What on earth are you talking about?
I said we have to evacuate everyone
- in town before tonight or...
- Shut your mouth.
"The comet will split and strike the town"?
"Itomori Town Hall"
"Over 500 people will die"?
How dare you spout such nonsense?
If you're serious, then you're sick.
Madness must be from the Miyamizu side.
I'll get someone to drive you
to a hospital in the city.
I'll listen to you after
a doctor examines you.
You son of a...
Mitsuha! No...
Who...
Who are you?
See you later at the festival.
Let's meet at the shrine.
- Don't be late.
- Bye!
- See you.
- Later.
You shouldn't go!
Get out of town. Tell your friends.
What are you saying?
Mitsuha!
- What was that?
- Let's go.
What are you doing?
Could Mitsuha...
Could she have persuaded them?
Is it my fault?
Yotsuha, leave town with
Grandma before nightfall.
You'll die if you stay here!
What are you saying?
Yesterday you suddenly went to Tokyo.
What's wrong with you?
Tokyo?
Hey, Mitsuha!
How did it go with your old man?
Hey, Mitsuha?
What's wrong with her?
No idea.
Are you there?
Is something over there?
Let me use your bike.
Hey, what the...
Hey, Mitsuha!
What about our plan?
Get ready as planned!
Please!
I'm Taki again.
What's Taki doing here?
The town...
is gone.
At that moment... did I...
die?
Taki. Taki.
Don't you remember me?
I'm going to Tokyo.
What? Now?
Why?
A date.
You have a boyfriend in Tokyo?
Not my date.
I'll come home tonight.
If I suddenly showed up,
would I bother him? Surprise him?
He might not like it.
The number you are trying to call
is not available...
There's no way we could meet.
But what if we did?
What should I do? Would I annoy him?
Would it be awkward?
"Tiamat Makes Closest Approach Tomorrow"
Or maybe...
he'd be a bit glad to see me?
The number you've called
is not available...
There's no way we could meet.
But...
one thing is certain.
If we see each other, we'll know.
That you were the one who was inside me.
That I was the one who was inside you.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
That time 3 years ago,
before I got to know you...
Taki.
Urn... It's me.
Don't you remember me?
Who are you?
I'm sorry.
But he's Taki.
Weird girl.
This is Yotsuya Station.
Hey!
What's your name?
Mitsuha!
My name is Mitsuha!
That time 3 years ago, you came...
to see me!
Taki?
Mitsuha!
You're here, aren't you? Inside my body!
Taki!
Taki, where are you?
It's Mitsuha.
I can hear her, but...
Taki, where are you?
Taki!
Taki, are you...
there?
It's twilight-"kataware-doki."
Mitsuha.
Taki.
Taki. It's really you.
Taki!
I came to see you.
It wasn't easy because
you were so far away.
But how? At that moment, I...
I drank your kuchikamisake.
You drank that?
You idiot! Pervert!
Oh yeah, and you touched my boobs!
How do you know that?
Yotsuha saw it.
Oh! Sorry, I couldn't help it!
It was just once.
Just once?
Doesn't matter how many times! Jerk.
Sorry.
Oh, this...
Oh. Really, Why'd you come see me
before I knew you?
There's no way I'd recognize you.
Here. I kept it for 3 years.
Now you keep it.
Yes.
How is it?
Not bad.
You're lying!
No, I... Sorry.
You're really so...
Mitsuha, you still have things to do.
Listen.
It's coming.
Don't worry. You've still got time.
Yes, I'll try.
Kataware-doki is almost...
over.
Hey, Mitsuha.
So we don't forget when we wake up...
Let's write our names on each other. Here.
OK!
Mitsuha?
Hey, Mitsuha?
I wanted to tell you.
Wherever you are in the world,
I'll search for you.
Your name is Mitsuha.
It's OK. I remember.
Mitsuha. Mitsuha. Mitsuha.
Your name is Mitsuha.
Your name is...
Who are you?
Why did I come here?
I came here to see her.
To save her. I wanted her to be alive.
Who was it? Who?
Who did I come to see?
Someone dear to me. I don't want to forget.
I shouldn't forget!
Who? Who? Who? Who?
What's your name?
Caught in a never-ending game. Seems
like the world's still trying to tame me
If that's the way I will obey.
Beautifully struggle everyday
Taki. Taki. Taki.
It's OK. I remember. I'll never forget!
Taki. Taki.
Your name is Taki!
"Itomori Substation"
Tessie!
Mitsuha! Where've you been?
He said sorry for breaking your bike.
- Huh? Who did?
- I did.
Explain everything to me later.
That's going to fall? Really?
Yes! Saw it with my own eyes!
What? You saw it, huh?
Then I guess we got no choice.
Now we're both criminals!
"Broadcasting Room"
What? I really have to do it?
When the town's power goes out,
the equipment there should work on backup.
Please, Sayaka!
Repeat it as much as you can!
Woo-hoo! You can do it!
Oh, to heck with it!
Soon, you think?
I've no idea!
What was that?
Look over there
At an unprecedented speed
I will drive right into you
And when I dozed off into
a lukewarm can of soda
I dreamed of a world so far from here,
that's not on the map
Searching outside of the classroom window
or in summer morning that's
brought from the commuting train
Hey. look!
This is Itomori Town Hall.
An explosion has occurred
at the substation.
- An accident?
- An explosion?
There is danger of further explosions
and forest fires.
Residents in the following areas,
please evacuate to Itomori High School.
Kadoiri District, Sakagami District,
The broadcast isn't from here?
Who is it, then?
Miyamori District...
Oyazawa District...
Let's go, Mitsuha!
Tessie!
Run, everyone! Forest fire!
Forest fire! Please evacuate!
Run! Fire!
It's not safe here! Please evacuate!
We don't have enough time! Mitsuha!
What's wrong?
His name... I can't remember his name.
Look, I don't know.
You started all this!
We can't evacuate everyone by ourselves!
Go persuade your father!
Everyone run! Go to the high school!
Oh, Mitsuha.
It's no terrorist attack!
What's Chubu Electric saying?
They're still checking!
No forest fire yet? Are you sure?
OK!
Stop this broadcast!
Figure out where it's coming from!
The Takayama sensor station called!
The high school?
Again, residents in the following areas,
evacuate to Itomori High School... Oh!
What are you doing? Turn that off!
Sayaka!
Oh no.
What have you done, Sayaka!
This is Itomori Town Hall.
We are currently checking on the accident.
Please don't panic and stay
where you are for further notice.
Stay put, they said.
What's going on?
So we stay put?
Come on, you should all evacuate!
The high school is the shelter!
Katsuhiko!
What are you doing?
Sorry, Mitsuha.
It's over.
It's really splitting apart!
- Look at that!
- Wow!
Please look! The comet has split in two
and meteors are falling!
Nobody predicted this.
We have a mystical view here.
So the comet's nucleus split?
Did tidal forces affect...
The comet isn't within the Roche limit
so the nucleus itself must have...
In the past, Comet Shoemaker-Levy 9
broke and collided with Jupiter in 1994.
At least 21 fragments...
I have to go there look!
Is it dangerous?
They will probably melt
before reaching the ground
and the probability of a meteor crashing
into a residential area is small...
To predict the trajectory...
To be witnessing such a magnificent
celestial event, and...
That we're witnessing this live
is extremely fortunate
for those of us living in this age.
Hey. Who are you?
Who? Who?
Who is that?
Someone dear to me. I shouldn't forget.
I didn't want to forget!
Who? Who? Who are you?
What's your name?
It's broken!
So we don't forget when we wake up,
let's write our names on each other.
"I love you"
Even the way that you loved.
I swear I could smell the scent of yours.
And in the way that you walked.
I could hear that bright laughter of yours.
I can't remember your name with this...
Make sure that
it's burned into the back of my eyes.
It's not a right that I'm due,
my duty that is must have been kept.
Dad!
- Mitsuha!
Not you again...
It was almost as if it
were a scene from a dream.
Nothing more, nothing less
than a beautiful view.
Words like 'tomorrow' or 'future or 'fate',
no matter how far they extend their hands.
We breathe, we dream, we raise our love, in
a timeless land that is far out of reach.
Even the second, hour hands of the clock, they
look at us sideways as they tick and took.
How I hope to have forever to spend.
This life, no - all future lives
right here in this world with you.
What am I doing here?
The next station is Yoyogi.
Please mind the door.
I'm always searching for something.
This feeling has possessed
me for some time.
I applied because...
The landscapes people live in...
To build a city's landscape...
You never know when Tokyo
might disappear as well.
So I want to help build landscapes that
leave heartwarming memories...
How many interviews have you had?
I haven't kept track.
- Can't see you landing a job.
- Thanks a lot!
Maybe it's because of that suit.
We're not that different!
I have 2 job offers.
I have 8.
"LINE: You have a new message."
I'm not sure if I'm
searching for a person or a place,
or if I'm just searching for a job.
Oh, you're job-hunting?
I haven't had much luck.
Maybe it's because of that suit.
Does it look that bad?
What brings you here today?
I came nearby for work
so I figured I'd say hi to you.
"8 years since the comet disaster"
We went to Itomori once, didn't we?
You were still in high school, so it was...
- 5 years ago.
- That long?
Seems like I've forgotten a lot.
I, too, no longer remember
much from back then.
Maybe we had a disagreement;
the other two returned to Tokyo without me.
I spent the night alone on some mountain.
That's about all I remember.
But at one point, I was inexplicably drawn
to the events surrounding that comet.
Half of a comet destroyed
a town in that disaster.
But most of the town's residents
were miraculously unhurt.
"Evacuation of residents
to high school grounds confirmed"
The entire town happened
to be holding an emergency drill
"An unprecedented natural disaster"
and most of its residents
were outside the blast zone.
"Residents safe"
"Disaster Foretold?"
The sheer luck and coincidence
sparked various rumors.
"Mayor Miyamizu's hidden agenda"
I intently read those articles back then.
"Mysterious explosion at the substation"
What had caught my interest so much
is now a mystery to me.
I didn't even know anybody in that town.
Thanks for today. This is far enough.
You will be happy someday too.
I feel like I'm always searching
for something, for someone.
"Construction company job interview"
I want to go to another bridal fair.
They're all the same.
Shinto-style is nice too.
You wanted a wedding in a chapel.
Oh, and Tessie.
Lose the beard before the wedding.
I'll lose 3 kg.
You're eating a cake.
I'll start tomorrow.
Thank you for coming.
"Itomori, the Town that Vanished"
"October 4, 2013-Itomori vanished."
Why does the scenery
of a town that no longer exists
wring my heart so much?
I was always searching...
searching...
for someone!
Hey!
Haven't we met?
I thought so too!
Your name is...